[
    {
        "question": "Ne man ne (<em>sculan</em>) #### drincan oððe etan binnan Godes huse — No man shall drink or eat within God's house",
        "correctAnswer": "sceal",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the third person present and modifying 'drican' so it becomes 'sceal'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Mæssepreost (<em>sculan</em>) #### habban mæsseboc — A mass-priest shall have a mass-book",
        "correctAnswer": "sceal",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the third person present and modifying 'habban' so it becomes 'sceal'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>sculan</em>) #### gehiran hwæt Paulus cwæð — They should listen to what Paul said",
        "correctAnswer": "scoldon",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the plural past and modifying 'gehiran' so it becomes 'scoldon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þus wæs gewriten be me: þæt ic þrowian (<em>sculan</em>) #### and arisan of deaðe on ðam þriddan dæge — This was decreed about me: that I should suffer, and arise from death on the third day",
        "correctAnswer": "scolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the first person past and modifying 'þrowian' so it becomes 'scolde'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða axode heo hine hwæðer heo (<em>sculan</em>) #### þa næglæs mid hire læden — Then she asked him whether she should carry the nails with her",
        "correctAnswer": "scolde",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the third person past and modifying 'læden' so it becomes 'scolde'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nu we (<em>sculan</em>) #### herian heofonrices weard — Now we shall praise the guardian of the kingdom of heaven",
        "correctAnswer": "sculon",
        "explanation":"Here 'sculan' is in the plural past and modifying 'herian' so it becomes 'sculon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hu (<em>magan</em>) #### blind man oðerne lædan? — How may a blind man lead another?",
        "correctAnswer": "mæg",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the third person present and modifying 'lædan' so it becomes 'mæg'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Witodlice ic (<em>magan</em>) #### ma secgan — Truly I may say more",
        "correctAnswer": "mæg",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the first person present and modifying 'secgan' so it becomes 'mæg'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Swa feor swa he (<em>magan</em>) #### on þrim dagum gesiglan — As far as he might sail in three days",
        "correctAnswer": "meahte",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the third person past and modifying 'gesiglan' so it becomes 'meahte'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo þone þeow findan ne (<em>magan</em>) #### — She couldn't find the servant",
        "correctAnswer": "meahte",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the third person past and modifying 'findan' so it becomes 'meahte'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Peter, forhwon ne (<em>magan</em>) #### þu ane tid wacian mid me? — Peter, why could you not watch with me for an hour?",
        "correctAnswer": "meahtest",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the second person past and modifying 'wacian' so it becomes 'meahtest'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Fela þinga we (<em>magan</em>) #### writan — We can write about many things",
        "correctAnswer": "magon",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the plural present and modifying 'writan' so it becomes 'magon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sprec us æfter urum andgyte, þæt we (<em>magan</em>) #### understandan þa þing þe þu specst — Speak to us according to our knowledge, so that we may understand those things of which you speak",
        "correctAnswer": "magon",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the plural present and modifying 'understandan' so it becomes 'magon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie ne (<em>magan</em>) #### þa wealas flieman — They could not expel the foreigners",
        "correctAnswer": "meahton",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the plural past and modifying 'flieman' so it becomes 'meahton'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie þohton hu hie hine acwellan (<em>magan</em>) #### — They thought how they might kill him",
        "correctAnswer": "meahton",
        "explanation":"Here 'magan' is in the plural past and modifying 'acwellan' so it becomes 'meahton'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic eode to minan abbode Ælfwine and bead hine þæt ic (<em>motan</em>) #### norþ faran — I went to my abbot Alfwin and told him that I must travel north",
        "correctAnswer": "moste",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the first person singular past and modifying 'faran' so it becomes 'moste'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa wearð seo cwen gegladod, þæt heo (<em>motan</em>) #### ðone maðm on moldan findan — Then the queen became gladened that she was able to find the treasure in the ground",
        "correctAnswer": "moste",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the third person singular past and modifying 'findan' so it becomes 'moste'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic restan ne (<em>motan</em>) #### — I am not able to rest",
        "correctAnswer": "mot",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the first person singular present and modifying 'restan' so it becomes 'mot'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwænne (<em>motan</em>) #### ic hine geseon? — When may I see him?",
        "correctAnswer": "mot",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the first person singular present and modifying 'geseon' so it becomes 'mot'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa hwile þe hi wæpna wealdan (<em>motan</em>) #### — As long as they can weild weapons",
        "correctAnswer": "moston",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the plural present and modifying 'wealdan' so it becomes 'moston'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt we (<em>motan</em>) #### his willan gewyrcan ðurh sume weldæde — That we can work his will through some good deed",
        "correctAnswer": "moston",
        "explanation":"Here 'motan' is in the plural present and modifying 'gewyrcan' so it becomes 'moston'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic ne (<em>cunnan</em>) #### understandan — I cannot understand",
        "correctAnswer": "can",
        "explanation":"Here 'cunnan' is in the first person present and modifying 'understandan' so it becomes 'can'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>cunnan</em>) #### eow læran — I can teach you",
        "correctAnswer": "can",
        "explanation":"Here 'cunnan' is in the first person present and modifying 'læran' so it becomes 'can'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie dydon swa hie (<em>cunnan</em>) #### — They did as they could",
        "correctAnswer": "cuþon",
        "explanation":"Here 'cunnan' is in the plural past and modifying 'dydon' so it becomes 'cuþon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Men ne (<em>cunnan</em>) #### secgan to soðe — Men could not say for sure",
        "correctAnswer": "cunnon",
        "explanation":"Here 'cunnan' is in the plural present and modifying 'secgan' so it becomes 'cunnon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þone soþan geleafan to (<em>bodian</em>) #### — In order to preach the true faith",
        "correctAnswer": "bodienne",
        "explanation":"Here 'bodian' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'bodienne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo onfeng þæt land, mynster to (<em>timbrian</em>) #### — She siezed that land in order to build a monastery",
        "correctAnswer": "timbrienne",
        "explanation":"Here 'timbrian' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'timbrienne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nys þe alyfed to (<em>habban</em>) #### þines broðer wif — It is not permitted to have your brother's wife",
        "correctAnswer": "hæbbenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'habban' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'hæbbenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie næfdon hlaf to (<em>etan</em>) #### — They didn't have bread to eat",
        "correctAnswer": "etenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'etan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'etenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ut eode se sædere his sæd to (<em>sawan</em>) #### — Out went the farmer, in order to sow his seeds",
        "correctAnswer": "sawenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'sawan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'sawenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gehire gif hwa earan hæbbe to (<em>hieran</em>) #### — Hear, if one has ears to hear!",
        "correctAnswer": "hierenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'hieran' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'hierenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Eaþere ys olfende to (<em>faran</em>) #### þurh nædle þyrel þonne se rica on godes rice ga — It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for the rich to go to god's kingdom",
        "correctAnswer": "farenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'faran' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'farenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie wilniað lof and wuldor to hæbbenne (<em>habban</em>) #### — They wished to have praise and glory",
        "correctAnswer": "hæbbenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'habban' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'hæbbenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ferdon to Francrice, þæt land to (<em>hergian</em>) #### — They went to France in order to plunder that land",
        "correctAnswer": "hergienne",
        "explanation":"Here 'hergian' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'hergienne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo ferde to circe, þæt godspell to (<em>hieran</em>) #### — She went to church to hear the gospel",
        "correctAnswer": "hierenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'hieran' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'hierenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Freolic to (<em>libban</em>) #### — In order to live free",
        "correctAnswer": "libbenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'libban' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'libbenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Werode to (<em>helpan</em>) #### on gefeohte — In order to help the people in battle",
        "correctAnswer": "helpenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'helpan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'helpenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wið fefre hylpþ wæter to (<em>drincan</em>) #### — Against fever it helps to drink water",
        "correctAnswer": "drincenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'drincan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'drincenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Heo ferde to Eoferwice, þa wicingas to (<em>helpan</em>) #### — She went to York in order to help the vikings",
        "correctAnswer": "helpenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'helpan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'helpenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Under þinum anwealde ic wilnie to (<em>wunian</em>) #### — Under your rule I should want to live",
        "correctAnswer": "wunienne",
        "explanation":"Here 'wunian' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'wunienne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "To helle gecuman to (<em>helpan</em>) #### Adames cyne — Come to Hell in order to help Adam's kin",
        "correctAnswer": "helpenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'helpan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'helpenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Mæst þearf is to (<em>gehealdan</em>) #### rihtne cristendom — It is most necessary to keep correct christianity",
        "correctAnswer": "gehealdenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'gehealdan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'gehealdenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie sealdon Ceolwulfe Myrcna rice to (<em>healdan</em>) #### — They gave Ceolwulf the kingdom of Mercia to hold",
        "correctAnswer": "healdenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'healdan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'healdenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt ðæt folc hæfð genoh to (<em>drincan</em>) #### — In order that that people have enough to drink",
        "correctAnswer": "drincenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'drincan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'drincenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He ferde þa siþþan to (<em>feohtan</em>) #### wið þone casere — He went then afterwards in order to fight with the emperor",
        "correctAnswer": "feohtenne",
        "explanation":"Here 'feohtan' loses the —an suffix and gains 'enne' to make the inflected infinitive 'feohtenne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He wilnode þæt þæt folc wære (<em>gecierran</em>) #### to Criste — He always wished that that people might be converted to Christ",
        "correctAnswer": "gecierred",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'cierran' is in the past tense and modifed by 'wære' so it becomes 'gecierred'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Com se Hælend on Galileam godspell (<em>bodian</em>) #### — The holy one came into Galilea, preaching the gospel",
        "correctAnswer": "bodiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'bodian' is in the present tense and modifed by 'com' so it becomes 'bodiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa com he and fand hie (<em>slæpan</em>) ####, and cwæþ to Petre, 'Simon, slæpst þu?' — Then he came and found them sleeping, and said to Peter, 'Simon, do you sleep?'",
        "correctAnswer": "slæpende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'slæpan' is in the present tense and modifying the pronoun 'hie' so it becomes 'slæpende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning hæfde þone mynster (<em>getimbrian</em>) #### — The king had built the monastery",
        "correctAnswer": "getimbrod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'getimbrian' is in the past tense and modifed by 'hæfde' so it becomes 'getimbrod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "&AELIG;r ðæm ðe Rome (<em>getimbrian</em>) #### wære — Before Rome was built",
        "correctAnswer": "getimbrod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'getimbrian' is in the past tense and modifed by 'wære' so it becomes 'getimbrod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Sceal beon (<em>gebodian</em>) #### on minum naman forgifenyss — Forgiveness shall be preached in my name",
        "correctAnswer": "gebodod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'bodian' is in the past tense and modifed by 'beon' so it becomes 'gebodod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se feorða heafodricu is Romane, þe giet (<em>ricsian</em>) #### sindon — The fourth empire is Roman, which is yet reigning",
        "correctAnswer": "ricsiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'ricsian' is in the present tense and modifed by 'sindon' so it becomes 'ricsiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þu eart (<em>gelufian</em>) #### — You are loved",
        "correctAnswer": "gelufod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'gelufian' is in the past tense and modifed by 'eart' so it becomes 'gelufod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Apollonius ongeat þæt he (<em>gelufian</em>) #### wæs fram þæm mædene — Apollonius perceived that he was loved by that maiden",
        "correctAnswer": "gelufod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'gelufian' is in the past tense and modifed by 'wæs' so it becomes 'gelufod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þis (<em>lufian</em>) #### wif — This loving wife",
        "correctAnswer": "lufiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'lufian' is in the present tense and modifying the noun 'wif' so it becomes 'lufiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo sawl bið (<em>libban</em>) #### — The soul is living",
        "correctAnswer": "libbende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'libban' is in the present tense and modifed by 'bið' so it becomes 'libbende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ne miht ðu me geseon; ne syhð me nan (<em>libban</em>) #### man — You cannot see me; no living man sees me",
        "correctAnswer": "libbiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'libban' is in the present tense and modifying the noun 'man' so it becomes 'libbiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se halig abbod wæs fela wundra (<em>wyrcan</em>) #### — The holy abbot was working many wanders",
        "correctAnswer": "wyrcende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'wyrcan' is in the present tense and modifed by 'wæs' so it becomes 'wyrcende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "God cwæð ða: Gewurðe leoht and leoht wæs (<em>wyrcan</em>) #### — God then said: 'Let there be light', and light was made.",
        "correctAnswer": "geworht",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'wyrcan' is in the past tense and modifed by 'wæs' so it becomes 'geworht'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þær wæs þære sunnan anlycnys (<em>wyrcan</em>) #### of golde — There the sun's likeness was made from gold",
        "correctAnswer": "geworht",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'wyrcan' is in the past tense and modifed by 'wæs' so it becomes 'geworht'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic wunie on þæm (<em>gehergian</em>) #### lande — I live in the plundered land",
        "correctAnswer": "gehergodan",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'hergian' is in the past tense and modifying the noun 'land' so it becomes 'gehergodan'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa Deniscan leode ferdon mid sciphere (<em>hergian</em>) #### and sleande wide geond land — The Danish people travelled with a navy plundering and killing widely around the land",
        "correctAnswer": "hergiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'hergian' is in the present tense and modified by 'ferdon' so it becomes 'hergiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie wæron (<em>hergian</em>) #### on Scotlande — They were plundering in Scotland",
        "correctAnswer": "hergiende",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'hergian' is in the present tense and modified by 'wæron' so it becomes 'hergiende'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On þissum geare wæs Gypeswic (<em>gehergian</em>) #### — In this year, Ipswich was plundered",
        "correctAnswer": "gehergod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'hergian' is in the past tense and modified by 'wæs' so it becomes 'gehergod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic eom (<em>lufian(</em>) #### — I am loved",
        "correctAnswer": "gelufod",
        "explanation":"Here the verb 'lufod' is in the past tense and modified by 'eom' so it becomes 'gelufod'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]
